A Finding Aid to the Gene Davis Papers, 1920-2000, bulk 1942-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.davigene
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1943-1990; Series 2; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-3, OV 19
  - N, 1951-1985 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Contains letter from J.B. Neuman, the New Museum, and an exhibition announcement from Barnett Newman
  - Steven W. Naifeh, circa 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1972-1980 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - National Life Insurance Company, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Neiman-Marcus Store, Bal Harbour, Florida, 1970-1987 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Walter A. Netsch, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - John Nichols, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Gerald Nordland, 1964-1982 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Percy North, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Nova Scotia College of Art and Design (Gerald Ferguson, Seth Siegelaub), 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - O, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Contains letters from Oklahoma Art Center and Osuna Gallery
  - Brian O'Doherty, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Oliver T. Carr Company, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Oxford Polytechnic (Tom Porter), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - P, 1946-1990 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    Includes letter from Norman Vincent Peale to Gene Davis's mother, and letters from Pyramid Galleries
  - Pace Editions, Inc., 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - The Phillips Collection, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Preston Phillips, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Poindexter Gallery (New York), 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Ralph Pomeroy, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Tom Porter, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Praeger Publishers, Inc., 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Max Protetch, Protetch-Rivkin, Protetch-McIntosh, 1971-1985 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Ann Purcell, circa 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Q-R, 1942-1985 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    Contains letters from Rolf Ricke, Barbara Rose, Gloria Ross, and a condolence card from Nancy and Ronald Reagan
  - S, 1954-1985 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    Contains letters from Roy Slade, the Society of Washington Artists, Willoughby Sharp, Therese Schwartz, and Sable Gallery.
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    See also Gerald Nordland
  - Frederic W. Schwartz, Jr., 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - William Seitz, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    See also Museum of Modern Art
  - Skidmore College Summer in Experiment, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Art, or National Museum of American Art, 1966-1985 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    See also Tom Messer
  - Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Walter Stern, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Studio International, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Mary Swift, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    Contains a photographic print of a portrait of Davis
  - T, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    Contains a letter from Alma Thomas
  - Tate Gallery, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - U, 1964-1980 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - U.S. Olympic Editions by Kennedy Graphics, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - University of Maryland, 1967-1985 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - University of Missouri, Kansas City, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - University of Utah, Utah Museum of Fine Arts, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - V, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Annemarie Verna, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Vesti Corporation, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - André Pascalis Volant de La Barre, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - W, 1960-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Walker Art Center, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Donald Wall, circa 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Washington Gallery of Modern Art, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Washington Post, 1961-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Washington Project for the Arts, circa 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Who's Who, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - James Witt, circa 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Y, 1969-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - First Names Only, Unsigned, and Envelopes Only, 1945-1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Illustrated Letter from Douglas Davis, from Box 1, folder 60 (Box OV 19)
- Interviews and Lectures, 1964-1983; Series 3; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3
  Series contains interviews with Gene Davis in the form of sound recordings and transcripts. Many of the interviews were broadcast or published. Also found is a single lecture by Davis given in 1969 at the National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian Institution, entitled “Contemporary Painting.” The Rose, Wall, and Hopps interviews with Davis (1971 and 1973) were later edited and published in a monograph in 1975. Edited transcripts related to that publication are found with original transcripts in this series. The Squirru and Voice of America interviews, as well as the Davis lecture, are on 4 sound tape reels, and the Hopps interview is on 1 sound cassette.
  Arrangement is chronological. Galley proofs from the Donald Wall publication are found in the Writings series.
  - Interview with Rafael Squirru, Pan American Union, circa 1964; 2 sound tape reels (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Suggestions for an Interview with Gene Baro," for Studio International, circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Contemporary Painting," Lecture by Davis at the National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian Institution, 1969 August 26; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "A Conversation with Gene Davis" by Barbara Rose, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Interview by Donald Wall, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "An Interview with Gene Davis" by Walter Hopps, 1973 October; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Voice of America Interview, 1974 April 3; 1 sound tape reels (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Reel 2 of 2 only. Location of Reel 1 of 2 unknown.
  - Interview with David Tannous for Art in America, circa 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "A Conversation with Gene Davis" by Jean Lawlor Cohen, circa 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Interview by Mary Swift, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Interview with Lisa Lyons, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Interview by John Gerard, Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Interview by Jerry Clapsaddle and Percy North, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Business and Estate Records, 1942-1990; Series 4; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, 17, OV 20
  Series contains business records related to Davis’s art career, including records of artwork, prices, sales, contracts, financial and legal records, gallery and museum files, records related to the construction of Davis’s home studio in 1970, and a few teaching records. In general, records from Davis’s lifetime are found throughout the series and records created after Davis’s death in 1985 are filed under Estate of Gene Davis. An exception is the Charles Cowles Gallery and Hokin Gallery files, which contain records of the estate inventory, sales, and loans. Records filed under Estate of Gene Davis mainly reflect Florence Davis’s efforts to document the works of her husband, and to manage their exhibition, promotion, and sale after April 1985. Gallery files contain inventory lists, sales records, and some correspondence and span Davis’s career. Museum files typically contain loan agreements, shipping records, insurance appraisals, records related to gifts and purchase of artwork, and invoices for artwork reproductions. Private sales include records of sales made directly by Davis to individual and corporate buyers, including his large-scale installation at Neiman Marcus in Boca Raton, Florida. Davis’s exhibition Child and Man: A Collaboration (1983), which featured children’s art juxtaposed with his own and curated by Washington Project for the Arts, is documented in a series of files for each of the five venues. The construction of Davis’s home studio is documented with architectural drawings, correspondence, invoices, and 13 super 8 mm film reels shot by Davis.
  Arrangement is alphabetical, with major headings grouping gallery, museum, and estate records. Additional material related to many of the transactions documented here, particularly related to sales and exhibitions, are found in series 2, Correspondence. Photographs of artwork and exhibitions are in series 7, Photographs.
  - Art Income and Expenses, 1965-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Artwork Lists, circa 1968-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Artwork Price Lists, circa 1960-1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Artwork Provenance, circa 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Contracts, 1962-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Estate of Gene Davis (Box 3)
    - Card Catalog of Artworks, circa 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Financial Records, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Fine Art Appraisal, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Gifts to Museums, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Legal Correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Notes, circa 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Photo Documentation of Damaged Paintings, after 1985 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Photo Documentation of Harrison Street Storage, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Files for Child and Man: A Collaboration (Box 3)
    - General File, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Joslyn Art Museum, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Joseph and Mary Muscarelle Museum, College of William and Mary, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Polk Museum, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Tampa Museum, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Gallery Files (Box 3)
    - General File, 1969-1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Floor Plans, circa 1965-1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Oversized floor plan in OV 20
    - Axiom Gallery, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, General File, 1982-1990 (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
      2 of 5 folders
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, General File, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
      3 of 5 folders
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, Condition Reports, circa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, Notes, circa 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, Printed Material, circa 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, Photographs of Artwork, circa 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Dorry Gates, Inc., 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Droll/Kolbert Gallery, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Oversized price list in Box 17
    - Dunkelman Gallery, circa 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fischbach Gallery, 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Henri Gallery, 1968-1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Hokin Gallery, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - I. Irving Feldman Gallery, 1979-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Max Protetch, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - McIntosh/Drysdale Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Middendorf Gallery, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Pense Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Poindexter Gallery, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Washington Project for the Arts, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Insurance and Taxes, 1965; 1984; 1942 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Jury Action Notices, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Legal Records (Box 4)
    - Henri Gallery Law Suit, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - King Printing Law Suit, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mailing Lists, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Museum Files (Box 4)
    - General File, 1965-1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1969-1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Delaware Art Museum, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Joseph and Margaret Muscarelle Museum of Art, College of William and Mary, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian Institution, 1965-1979 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Neuberger Museum, SUNY Purchase, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Walker Art Center, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photo Documentation of Damaged Studio, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Print Sales, Petersburg Press Ltd., 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
  - Private Sales, 1969-1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Oversized floor plan for Neiman Marcus mural in OV 20
  - Receipts and Expenses, circa 1965-1978 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Studio Construction Records, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Studio Construction Film Footage, circa 1971; 13 Film reels super 8 mm (Box 4, Folder 43-49)
  - Teaching Records, 1968-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Price List from Box 4, folder 9 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Floor Plans from Box 3, folder 47 (Box OV 20)
  - Oversized Floor Plan from Box 4, folder 40 (Box OV 20)
- Writings, 1944-1990; Series 5; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-6, 17, 19
  Writings include notes, articles, statements, essays, books, and research material by and about Gene Davis. Writings by Gene Davis include artist statements, magazine and newspaper articles about art, news stories written as a White House correspondent for Transradio Press Service, exhibition-related texts, notes, and a proposal for the site-specific “Grass Painting” at the Kennedy Center in 1974. Artist’s statements were usually written for specific Davis exhibitions, and include a statement for the “Gene Davis Give-Away,” a happening undertaken with Douglas Davis and Ed McGowin in 1969. Several of Davis’s articles reflect specifically on the Washington, D.C. art scene. Most of the writings exist as typescripts. Photocopies of the published article are found for a few items.
  Writings by others include articles and books about Gene Davis by various authors, and research notes by Percy North. Articles are filed by author. One of the books is a handwritten satire by Jim Lodge documenting the installation of a large work by Davis in a private office. Other books with records in this series are monographs on Davis; one by Donald Wall (1975) and another by Steven Naifeh (1982). Materials found for Wall’s book include galley proofs for interviews of Davis conducted by Barbara Rose, Donald Wall, and Walter Hopps, and color proofs of the color plates. Materials found for the Naifeh book include an edited typescript of the text, black and white photographic prints of images from the book, and color transparencies and Chromalin prints of color plates. The photographs are heavily annotated with markup for print production, as well as some source information. Black and white photographs referred to as “reference prints” are photographs of Davis and others. The rest of the photographs and plates are of artworks.
  Research notes by Percy North include photocopied published material with annotations by North, notes, a list of articles collected, and notes updating the bibliography and exhibition list for Naifeh’s 1982 monograph.
  Writings by Gene Davis are filed first, alphabetically by title, form, or subject, followed by writings by others, filed alphabetically by author. Where multiple drafts exist for a piece, the draft that appears to be closest to final is filed at the front of the folder. Published versions of many of the writings are found in series 6, Printed Materials. Original transcripts and one sound recording from the interviews contained in the 1975 Donald Wall book are found in series 2, Interviews and Lectures.
  - Writings by Gene Davis (Box 5)
    - Artist Statements, circa 1962-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin Board Materials, circa 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Notes, circa 1960-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Untitled Fragments, circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - For Architecture Magazine, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Gene Baro (1924-1982) - A Tribute" (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Jacob Kainen's Recent Work", circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Journalism as a White House Correspondent, circa 1944-1948 (Box 5, Folder 9-12)
    - "A New York State of Mind" in the Washington Post, 1981 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - On Arshile Gorky, circa 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - On "Big" Al Carter, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - On Franz Bader, circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - On Douglas Davis, circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - On Mary Page Evans, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - On Max Protetch, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - On Pablo Picasso, circa 1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - On Working as a Journalist, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Options: Washington, 1981" (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Proposal for a Grass Painting", circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "A Rambling Love Note to the Phillips Collection" and "Campaign for the Phillips", circa 1960; 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Random Thoughts on Art" for Art International, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
    - Specifications for Canvas Stretchers, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Response to Irving Sandler Questionnaire, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Response to ArtForum Questionnaire, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Time Painting", circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Video Tape Ideas, circa 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      Oversized notes in OV 19
    - "Washington Art in the Fifties - An Artist's Memoir", circa 1979 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Articles by Others (Box 5)
    - Leslie Judd Ahlander, "The Emerging Art of Washington", 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Lawrence Alloway, "Nine Contemporary Painters, U.S.A.", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Gene Baro, "The Drawn Image", circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Gene Baro on Gene Davis, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Murray Bring, "Toast to Gene" for Middendorf Exhibition, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Jean Lawlor Cohen, on Gene Davis, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Jean Lawlor Cohen, "Washington Art History: The Fifties", circa 1988 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Timothy Hynes, "Gene Davis: Where Opposites Meet", 1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ken Jackson, "Gene Davis, Art Teacher", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Jacob Kainen, "Gene Davis and the Art of the Color Interval", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Pinky Kase, "Gene Davis: the Random and the Ordered", 1983 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Billy Kluver, Transcript of Oral Presentation on Proposed Cable Television Rules, 1971 March 26 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Donald Kuspit, "Gene Davis", circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Jane Livingston, "Gene Davis", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Sharon Michael, "Gene Davis: A Colorist Salutes the Stripe", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Steven Naifeh, "Going to Extremes: Artist Gene Davis Paints the Biggest Painting in History", 1979 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Steven W. Naifeh, "Niagara by Gene Davis: Walking a Bold Line between the Basic and the Banal", 1979 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Steven W. Naifeh, "Writing a Dissertation on a Living Artist", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Gerald Nordland, On Gene Davis, circa 1967 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Percy North, "Child and Man: A Collaboration", circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Percy North, "Gene Davis (1920-1985)", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Percy North on Sun Sonata, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Donald Wall, "Art Stripes Real? The Recent Paintings of Gene Davis", circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Donald Wall, "The Early Prophetic Paintings of Gene Davis", circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Donald Wall, "The Early Stripe Paintings of Gene Davis", circa 1969 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Donald Wall, "Gene Davis and Color Forming", circa 1967 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Donald Wall, "Gene Davis and the Issue of Complexity", circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Donald Wall, "Gene Davis: Confrontations with Architecture", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Donald Wall, "The Micro-Paintings of Gene Davis: An Architect's Response", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Donald Wall, On Gene Davis and Kenneth Noland, circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Donald Wall, "The Ubiquitous Stripe", circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Donald Wall, "2 Fragments of 'Great Thoughts'", circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Ralph Pomeroy, "The March of Time in Color", circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Books (Box 5)
    - "Big Ben" by Jim Lodge, circa 1976 (Box 5, Folder 67)
      A handmade satirical play and photo album about the stretching and hanging of Davis’s “Big Ben” canvas in a private office
    - Gene Davis by Donald Wall (1975) (Box 5)
      - Chronology, Biography, and Bibliography, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Galley Proofs and Color Plates, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 69-70)
        Oversized galley proof and color plate in OV 19
    - Gene Davis by Steven Naifeh (1982) (Box 5)
      - Bibliography, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - Biographical Material, circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Edited Typescript, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 73-77)
      - Notes from Gene Davis, circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Photographs, Black and White Reference Prints, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Photographs, Black and White Figures 1-40, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 80-83)
        Oversized photographs (figures 3 and 39) in Box 17
    - Gene Davis by Steven Naifeh (1982) (Box 6)
      - Photographs, Black and White Figures 41-91, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
        Oversized photographs in Box 17
      - Photographs, Color Plates 2-17, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5-9)
      - Photographs, Color Plates 18-46, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10-14)
      - Photographs, Color Plates 47-74, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15-19)
        Oversized color plates 56 and 58 in Box 17
      - Photographs, Color Plates 75-103, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 20-25)
        Oversized color plates in Box 17
  - Compilation of Critical Reviews of "Two Decades of American Painting" Exhibition (1966), circa 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Research by Percy North (Box 6)
    - Annotated Articles (1952-1981), circa 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 27-30)
    - List of Articles Collected, circa 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Notes, circa 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Photocopied Book and Catalog Excerpts (1964-1977), circa 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Updates to Bibliography and Exhibition List, circa 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Unsigned Exhibition Reviews and Articles, 1963; 1984 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Unsigned Research Notes, circa 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Oversized Photograph from Box 5, folder 80 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Photograph from Box 5, folder 83 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Photograph from Box 6, folder 3 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Color Plates from Box 6, folder 17 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Color Plates from Box 6, folder 19 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Color Plates from Box 6, folder 21 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Notes from Box 5, folder 32 (Box OV 19)
  - Oversized Galley Proof and Color Plate from Box 5, folder 69, 1944-1990; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 5-6, 17, OV 19 (Box OV 19)
- Printed Material, 1942-1990; Series 6; 5.2 Linear feet Boxes 7-11, 17-18, OV 20
  Series is arranged by type of material, and large groups such as catalogs and clippings are filed chronologically within each type. Drafts of many of the articles by or about Davis are found in series 5, Writings. Percy North’s notes and annotated photocopies related to her bibliographic research are also found in series 5. Additional printed material is found in series 1, Biographical Materials, and series 4, Business and Estate Records.